- ♪ In the not-too-distant
Future ♪
♪ Next Sunday AD ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ Not too different
From you or me ♪
♪ He worked at
Gizmonic Institute ♪
♪ Just another face
In a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ He did a good job
Cleaning up the place ♪
♪ But his boss didn't like him
So he shot him into space ♪
♪ We'll send him
Cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can find
La-la-la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ And we'll monitor his mind
La-la-la ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Joel can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies
Begin or end la-la-la ♪
♪ Because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ To make his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll call
Cambot! ♪
- ♪ Pan left ♪
- ♪ Gypsy! ♪
- ♪ Hi girl! ♪
- ♪ Tom Servo! ♪
- ♪ What a cool guy ♪
- ♪ Croooow! ♪
♪ Wisecracker ♪
♪ If you're wondering
How he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts
La-la-la ♪
♪ Then repeat to yourself
It's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ For Mystery Science
Theater 3000! ♪
ANNOUNCER:     30 seconds to
commercial sign.
- Hey, everybody.
Welcome to the experiment.
ANNOUNCER:  Commercial sign
in 15 seconds.
- We're playing
hide and seek
with the elusive
and inexplicable forces
which control the universe.
- We're still safe,
because the cosmic universe
has its eyes closed,
and it's counting to
6.02 times 10 to the 23rd.
JOEL:
Oh, oh, oh.
- I wanted to play hopscotch
with the impenetrable
mystery of existence,
but he stepped in a wormhole
and had to go innerly.
ANNOUNCECommercial sign in
five, four, three, two,
commercial sign now.
- We'll be right back.
( THEME MUSIC PLAYING )
- 97, 98, 99, 100.
Ready or not,
here we exist!
Oh, look, the cosmic universe
isn't even trying to hide.
- Rats.
- Oh, and feckless uber munses
are flexing
their zychites again.
- Huh?
- The sites
is barking down my snorkel.
- Oh.
- Okay, this is how
it goes down.
There's the chorus, and then
you come in after the bridge.
Legato.
Can you dig it?
Okay, and then
I start swinging
like it ain't
nobody's business,
and that is if my chops
are in shape, heh.
You know, chops.
( SCATTING )
Forget it.
Joel,
what could I do for you?
- What are you talking about?
You called us!
- Oh, that's right,
I called you.
I think you're supposed to do
the invention exchange.
- Uh, okay, this is
my invention exchange.
It's called
the  radio arm saw;
and, uh, it's based on
the premise that carpenters,
for the longest time,
would have apprentices
that would,
uh, study under them and do
some of the more mundane work,
and now a lot of young people
go right into the fast food
industry.
So, none of the carpenters
can afford them,
except for maybe Bob Villa.
But what this has is,
is a, uh, a circular saw
that I bolted onto a remote
control car, all right?
And you can pan it back now,
Cambot, and we'll show this.
And what we've got here
is a board, okay?
I rev up the,
I rev up the, uh, car.
Okay, there it's going.
It's kind of loud now
so, uh, just try to
pay attention anyway.
And it drives
right across like that,
and it saws the board
right in two.
- What's so great about that?
- It's based on the premise
that the further you are
away from the saw,
the better off
you're gonna be.
- ( LAUGHS ) huh?
- Oh, come on,
shake it off, Joel.
You're okay.
It could happen to anybody.
- You okay, Joel?
- No, it's all hot,
and it hurts and stuff.
- Aw.
- Well, that doesn't look
OSHE inspected or anything;
but, anyway, right now,
Dr. Forrester is going to
jam on our new invention.
Right, sir?
- That's right.
Thank you, Frank.
Now, earlier today, Joel,
I removed my own head
and fused it to the bell
of this baritone sax.
When Frank blows
into the mouthpiece, I wail.
- That's right.
I press the valve down here,
the music goes
round and round--
whoa, oh, oh, oh--
and it comes out here.
- Yes, I call
this little invention Dr. Sax.
Now I'd like to play for you
some of my favorite
John Coltrane charts.
Hit it, Frank.
An evil supreme,
an evil supreme,
an evil supreme.
Well, what do you think?
( JOEL COUGHING )
- You may have just
crossed that line.
I've never seen anything
so hideous,
so immoral, so atonal.
( COUGHING )
- Thank you.
Oh, I've got to clean out
his spit valve.
- Ugh, thank you, Frank.
- Well, Joel,
your movie this week
is preceded by
a little piece of tripe
that's very close
to my own heart,
called,
"The Phantom Creeps,"
and it stars our old friend,
Bela Lugosi,
as a lovable but fractured
mad scientist.
Bad print, bad sound,
bad for you.
Deal with it joyless prowl.
( BUZZER )
- Oh, we've got movie sign!
( MUSIC PLAYING )
- Okay.
- My goodness,
it's creeping.
It's really creeping.
( MUSIC PLAYING )
- Oh, it looks like
a Ding Dong with legs.
- Ford Beebe!
- Ford Beebe.
- Sheila MacRae,
I'm coming!
Goodnight, everybody!
- That's how I looked like
before my shave.
Now let's meet the cast.
- That's my roommate, Steve.
He's always on the phone
and always, always
in the bathroom.
- Cindy, she's not half bad,
if you know what I mean.
Kind of looks like Madonna.
Then it's Johnny and Ray.
Johnny is the talkative one.
Ray looks like Madonna.
- There's Pete and Repeat,
always sticking their ptooeys
where they don't belong either.
Blah.
Those were just my friends.
Let's meet the cast.
I forget who did what here.
I say shoot the picture.
Let God sort it out.
Heh, heh.
- Oh, "The Menacing Power."
That would be Con Edison,
I'm guessing.
- Oh, yeah, yeah.
- Maybe I shaved him too close--
the ultimate test
of the Helsinki formula.
Hey, I just invented
the Post-it notes.
- Wasn't he one of
the Smith Brothers?
- Yeah, or either trainer, Mark.
I'm not sure which one.
- Now to put him
in my stock pot.
- I knew him, Horatio.
- You're not going to let
that thing out again, are you?
- Certainly, there's work
to be done on it.
- It might get away like
it did last time.
- You dare mock me!
- I created it.
- I'm the god,
I'm the god!
- I can control it
or destroy it like you,
you whom I helped
escape from prison.
At the door--
go quickly.
- I'm gonna give him
such a pinch, ooh.
- Boy, is he in a bad mood.
- What's behind the panel,
Johnny?
- Oil can.
- Cool.
- I don't see what good it is.
The cops will never let
anything like that
walk down the street.
- Shut up.
He just plays tapes.
- What could the police
or anybody do
against an army like them?
- Well, they could give them
a plastic hassle, man,
that's what.
- Hello.
I'm Milton,
your brand new son.
- Oh, what's the big deal?
It's a big metal Richard Kiel.
- Uh, Gomer Pyle reporting
for duty, Sergeant Carter.
Shazam.
- Now, how much would you pay
for an all purpose
monster like this?
Wait, there's more.
- We control him.
He could crush
all opposition
and make me the most powerful
man in the world.
- Hey, watch it!
- Hey, uh, nice speech,
but he's trashing the place.
- Uh, he's programmed
to do Noel Abram's job.
Fix this in jiffy.
( SERVO MAKING ROBOTIC NOISES )
- Wait 'til I get him
on the straightaway.
- Uh, Dominos.
- There's a car outside.
That will be my wife.
She wants to take me away.
- She's got an extra job.
- She's afraid of
what I'm doing here;
yet, she knows
only a small part of it.
- Aha.
( MUMBLING )
- No thanks.
- Let me go in and talk to him
alone, Dr. Mallory.
He's been angry with you
ever since you refused to
continue to work with him.
- Thanks for the exposition.
- Because he was
working along lines
contrary to
the good of mankind.
- I know.
- Hey, who doesn't?
Give him a break.
- Sure.
- I hope I can stop him
before it's too late.
- I hate to have you
face him alone.
- Dressed like that.
-  Oh, I understand.
I think he really cares for me,
as much as
he can care for anyone.
- Except himself.
- Oh, talk about
vicious backstabbing.
- You're not going to tell her
about the new element
you discovered, are you?
- You mean upsy-daisy-um?
- But I have accomplished what
they told me was impossible.
- A funny Gallagher routine?
- Get me one of
the magnetized disks.
- But if you're determined
to face him alone,
I'll wait in there.
- In a sound proof booth.
- But won't your wife think--
- Silence!
- She knows nothing
of our love.
- I'm her.
- Alex!
- No, don't do that!
You scared the pants off me.
- Ann, my dear.
- You, you're glad to see me?
- Yes.
- Sure, as long as
the lights are out.
Okay, now beat it.
- I've been wanting a witness
to my great crime.
- Hm.
- Oh.
- Yes.
- Uh-huh.
- I told Mallory
and the others
there was a way to induce
a state of suspended animation
that couldn't be told
from death,
that I could find it.
- Uh, play a Kenny G album?
- They called me
a dreamer, a fool,
but now I have it!
And you shall see
and tell them. Come.
- Ah, you've really gone
over the edge this time, prof.
Ooh, I love what you've done
with the place.
- Now what goes on in here?
- You see this disk?
Watch.
- This is disk.
- Oh, I've seen this one.
- Now, tree, we've never met
before, have we?
Good.
- What's he have,
sea monkeys, sea monkeys?
Ah, looks like sea monkeys.
- This is an outrage.
Oosh!
- It will not come to you.
- Even spiders have taste.
- It will crawl
only to that disk,
which I have put there
by the plant.
That disk there is magnetized
by a positive ray
with my new element,
which is unknown to science.
- Mm-hm.
- And this little spider
carries the magnet.
- Mm-hm, mm-hm.
- And the two--
- Ah, can the balloon juice prop
and get on
with the parlor trick!
- Do that snappy pattern.
- Chopper always leaves you
laughing.
Ha, ha, ha, ha,
ha, ha, ha.
- I can see the string!
- Whoa!
- That's my new opening.
What do you think?
- You killed it!
ALEX: No, look.
- Great, you just invented
stop animation.
- Look there.
- ( indistinct )
- --under same circumstances.
- It's too bad that Mallory
is not here to see my triumph.
- I have seen it.
- You, you were spying!
- Call it that
if you wish, Alex,
but you made no secret of it.
Now my fear is what are you
going to do with it?
- I'll put it in your shorts,
you little stinker.
- Not hand it over
to the government,
as you would have me.
- I still think
that would be best.
It should be under control
for the good of mankind.
You would still receive credit
for its discovery.
- You just won't be able
to do it any club.
- But possibly--
- Never will I let it go.
Already a foreign government
has offered me millions.
Perhaps--
- Thousands.
- I shall sell to them.
- Don't you realize
what a terrific weapon
it would be in the hands
of unscrupulous people?
- Comedy club owners?
- Of course.
That is why they shall
pay me dearly for it.
- Alex, you must not.
- Then it is my duty to
inform the government at once.
- Alex, please!
- Ooh, what a look
I'll give you!
- God grant me the serenity
to accept the things
I cannot change and--
- All right.
If it is your duty,
do so, by all means,
but you will find it
a great mistake.
- What do you mean?
( SINISTER LAUGH BY ALEX )
- You shall soon learn,
all of you!
- The power of the dark one.
- I'm sorry, but he just
can't help being creepy.
- Your prescription
is ready, sir.
- Monk! Monk!
- No.
- Get the devisualizer.
- Ooh.
- Did you carry out
my instructions
regarding the work
to be done on this?
- Yes, sir.
- It's an electronic dance bot.
- But I was afraid to use it.
- I'm not afraid!
- Haim?
- L'chaim?
- They know everything
that I have,
but they know nothing
of the devisualizer.
- Uh, I think
it goes under the suit.
- It will conceal me
from my enemies.
- I'll stay here, tonight.
Perhaps I can see him again--
- If he'll have me,
the big galoot.
- --and persuade him
from his mad course.
- And I'll get in touch
with the government.
I've already talked
with Captain West
of the War Department
about Alex.
- And I'll give the names
of my colleagues
to Senator McCarthy.
- No, Ann,
they'll just keep him
and what he has found
under control,
so that he can't misuse it
or dispose of it
to a country that would.
- Ah!
- Oh, oh, I never
should've filled up
on that four-alarm chili.
Ooh, excuse me.
- Ow.
- Oh, burn the file
on the electric dance belt
and pick up my manhood.
It's under the chair.
- You have failed, Monk!
- What do you mean?
I wrote straight, no chaser,
around midnight.
I'll take that.
- But I will not fail.
I cannot.
- I'll call, if I need you.
- Goodnight, Ann.
- And I'll go call Roy Cone.
- Goodnight.
- Fits nice, works real--
oh, that's no dance beat.
- Say, that's a pretty good
Patrick Swayze.
- It is perfect,
but for a shadow.
- But can you come back?
- Surely.
- I must come back.
- Hm.
- Then I'll go to
Victoria's Secret.
- Heh-heh.
- Think you could steal me
some candy bars
or something someday?
It'd be really cool.
- And now with the phantom,
there is nothing
that I cannot do.
- If I had you.
- Just put some lace
on this dance belt.
Now, will our mystery guest
sign in, please?
- Aw, he gets all
the neat toys.
( SERVO AND CROW
MAKING ROBOTIC NOISES )
- Now, if you guys don't mind,
I've got a Michelin Man
reading in an hour.
ALEX: Nobody can find
our secret workshop
without the Iron Man helping.
- I am Iron Man.
- Oh, it conceals so cleverly.
Nobody could ever find it.
- Unless they're from
the Student Loan Association.
- I'll be entirely moved
by morning.
Pack what we need.
- Look at all the pizzas
that guy can hold.
- I'll, uh,
just let myself out.
- While the cat's away,
the mice will play.
- Oh, I love what you've done
with the place.
- I know,
I get compliments always.
Thank you.
- Oh, sorry, I didn't have
everything packed.
Come on,
set that down anywhere.
Can I get you a beer?
- Ah--
now turn your head
and clank.
- Hm, wow, this guy really knows
how to get the most
out of what limited space
he's got.
- I know.
He should be in
"Better Dungeons and Gardens."
- My private stock,
Glenfiddich, 30 years old.
- Just what science has needed.
- He's just blowing off
a little steam there.
- Quick, get Vicks
on the phone.
I've just invented
the vaporizer.
- They must never
know about you,
the source of all my power.
( THEME MUSIC PLAYING )
- From what you say,
Dr. Zorka has discovered
something very important.
- I'm sure he has--
highly dangerous, too.
- Zi umlaut?
- D7?
- Snackmaster?
- Have you made
any search for it?
- No, we thought we'd better
wait until you got here.
- Who are you, anyway?
- Let's look
in his laboratory.
- Aren't you going to
take that disk?
- Well, uh,
I'll get it later.
I'd hate to have
one of those spiders
find it in my pocket.
( LAUGHTER )
- Those fools!
Let them search.
- What's he looking at?
- They'll find nothing.
- We'll just break
right in here.
- I really like what
they've done in here
with the pastels
and the, uh, instruments.
- Yeah.
- A lot of equipment
seems to have been moved.
- Hm.
- We can talk Rank, a spy ring
guy will be with you.
- But--
- Hm?
- Unseen.
- Oh?
- Next, I'll show you
how to make a bass snagger.
- Your husband
smokes a popular brand.
- Columbian.
( LAUGHTER )
- He can't stand tobacco.
- Well, how about
his assistant?
- He can't stand smoking
his assistant, either.
- She's right.
Zorka worked alone.
- Okay, now,
you be the chauffeur.
I'll be the contessa.
We can play that game again--
ho, ho.
- We must be very
careful than ever,
that no one discovers the
entrance to our secret garage.
- Yeah, right, right, right.
- Whatever.
- Just get in there.
Get into this little
crawl space, you lard butt.
Geez. What a pain.
Oh, brother.
- I'll phone headquarters
and have his description
broadcast.
He'll picked up somewhere;
that is, if he still
answers his own description.
- I just love
informing on people.
- All clear?
- Yes, sir.
- Then we will go to meet
the agent of the spy ring.
- Aspiring to what?
- When last seen, he wore
striped trousers,
dark cornard tie
and cutaway coat.
- And a light blue Warner bra.
- Ooh.
- But it would take
one to carry the things
that are missing
from his laboratory.
- Hey, it's Gladys Kravitz.
- Yes, that's right.
Put this on the teletype
right away, would you?
- Let's see there.
- Pick up that man!
- What do you mean,
give him a ride?
- Yes!
- No, ask him out.
What do you think I mean?
- He might be useful to me.
- He's just my type,
AB negative.
- Hey, you guys going
to that dead concert?
Yeah, did you hear
Pigpen died?
- Pigpen is dead?
Oh!
- If Pigpen died,
I don't want to live either.
- What a long,
strange trip it's been.
- Hey, that's a rental.
It's on my card!
- I'm dead now.
Don't hitchhike, please.
- The man is dead.
- Don't hitchhike.
- How fortunate.
That simplifies everything.
- To you.
- Get Miss Daisy out of there.
- We will make it seem
that it is the famous Dr. Zorka
who has been killed.
- Oh.
- The old switcheroo.
- Good.
- Then we will get
another car, go home,
and see what
they are doing there.
- Then you'll be happy?
I don't think so.
- West speaking.
- Uh, just trying to do
what's right.
And you?
- Right, I've got it.
We'll fly right down there.
There's been a car found,
wrecked and burned
on Highway 10,
50 miles north of here.
- A car phone?
- Ah, just the thing
we're looking for.
- The contents of the pockets
indicated Dr. Zorka--
- Hi, I'm Speedy
the Alka-Seltzer-- ha, ha.
- You go with it?
- It's Coo-Coo
the bird girl.
- Such a shock.
ANN: I'll go.
I must know.
- If Pigpen is still alive.
- Warm up the plane,
will you, Jim?
Whenever you're ready,
Mrs. Zorka.
- Put that lampshade
on your head,
and tie femur bones
around your waist,
and dance naked
in the moonlight!
- Good one.
- I sure hope they have
those little salty sweet peanuts
on this flight.
- Hm.
- Oh.
- Good thing they still have
a broom closet on this plane.
- Hm.
- They are taking my wife
to identify the body
we left at the car.
She will know
it is not mine.
- What a hoot.
- She has one of my disks,
and she does know it.
I have just time enough to put
that spider into the plane.
- Am I whacky or what?
- She will go
into suspended animation,
so that she cannot
identify the dead man.
Then I will take her
from them, revive her.
- Only to put her
back to sleep again.
- Quick, we have to be there
as soon as the plane arrives.
- I like this so much,
I bought the company.
- It shouldn't take long.
- I'll check the lab equipment
and try to figure out
just what's missing.
Bye.
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
- So long.
- Bye, bye.
- So, Bill, ever flown
one of these shuttles before?
- Uh-oh, Raid!
- Hey, there's something
the matter with that door.
I'm sure I shut it.
- Hmph.
- Doesn't look to me
as if you did.
- Wiener.
- Whoa!
- This wasn't in my bag
when I left the house.
- You know,
if you bite one of those,
it'll spark in the dark.
- Some kind of disk
that we found on the plant.
ANN:
The one the spider went to.
- Are you certain
it wasn't in your bag before?
- Positive.
- Now, you're sure
you're not a klepto?
- I haven't seen
one of those things yet.
- Jim, I want to send it
back to the department.
Are you sure
you didn't find it
and take it
as sort of a keepsake?
- Why, of course, I didn't.
- Tell me, from where
the car was found,
have you any idea
where Dr. Zorka was going?
- None whatever.
( ANN SCREAMING )
- Well, the pilot's bombed.
- The pulls are out of order.
We have to bail out!
- What are you doing here?
Never mind.
- I'm the automatic pilot.
- Huh?
( MIKE AND BOTS SCREAMING )
- Get into this chute.
- Yes, sir.
- Oh, Captain Spaulding.
- Charlie Sheen,
Navy Seals.
- Nice.
- I think we're gonna
get out of here soon.
- Uh-oh.
- Hey, bomb those bots.
( MUSIC PLAYING )
- All right, and welcome
to Bela's okay discoveries.
My name is Joel.
A product that can allow you
to make anything at all explode?
We'll see it on today's show.
Then we'll be showing you
how to make
your neighbor's house
turn into instant rubble,
but that's in
the second segment.
Now, I'll introduce my guests,
Tom Servo and Crow.
- Thank you, thank you,
everybody,
and good day to you, Joel.
Now, what we have here--
can we pan over here
and get a little look at these?
Down here, it's called
the phantom creep.
Now, it's been in use
for Great Britain for years,
but not a lot of people
in the States
know anything about it.
- Looks like kind of a spider.
- Yeah, that's right.
Now, let's take a look
at this shirt here
that we've prepared
ahead of time.
It's been smeared
with axle grease,
a little blood,
some chocolate,
and a little
polychlorinated biphenyl.
- Oh, oh, I know
Cambot and I
wouldn't want that
to happen to us.
( APPLAUSE )
- Okay, so what
we want you to do
is attach one of those
little disks there
that you have in your hand.
- This disk?
That's it? I love it.
Okay, how much would you pay?
- Uh, we're not there yet.
- Okay, so we attach
the disk to the shirt,
and we bring in
our little phantom creep.
There it goes.
Can you see?
- Let me see.
There it goes.
- There it goes
right in there and--
- Ah!
- I love it!
- That's amazing, isn't it?
Okay, now, quickly, Joel.
- It's great.
Joel, Joel, now grab
that satellite dish there.
It's right behind you there.
- He's bending over.
He's grabbing the dish, yes.
- This is amazing, people,
absolutely amazing.
- Okay.
- Now watch.
- Now take the dish.
Now rub some black dirt into it,
just some ordinary black dirt.
- You can take it
right off the shirt there.
- But this is-- I can't.
This is the--
this is my satellite.
Come on, you guys.
- Oh, it will be fine.
It's okay, I promise.
- But it's right off
the Satellite of Love. Okay.
- It's okay.
- All right, just like--
come on, just like that?
- Now, everyone knows
the side facing the sun
takes a real beating.
I mean, it's 4,000 degrees
out there.
The other side,
no sun over there.
What happens
when I stand over here?
- Mm, you're out of the sun?
- That's right.
It's ice cold over here.
We take a little disk--
- Take one of those disks.
- --and put it
right in the center,
and here it comes.
- Watch.
- You see? Ah!
( APPLAUSE )
- Isn't that amazing, huh?
- That's fantastic!
Okay, I love it.
My heart says yes,
but my heart says how much?
- Okay, now, Joel,
if you were to sneak
into a mad scientist's lair
and try to buy all this,
well, it would cost you
well into the millions,
wouldn't it?
- That's right, Servo, right.
The generic engineering alone
would run hundreds
of thousands of dollars,
not to mention
the arachno pyro techniques.
- All right, you know me.
I'm a hard sell.
Come on,
let's make a deal.
Make it better.
- Okay, now, I'm glad
you asked us for that.
We're going to sweeten the deal
a little bit for you here.
Now, we're going to throw in
the napalm spider.
- Uh-huh, uh-huh,
that's this right here, right.
- That's right.
- Now, is that jelly gasoline?
- Oh, it's not just
jelly gasoline, Joel,
but a highly effective
antipersonnel device.
- Mm-hm, I see, okay.
But what's the deal?
There are like three spiders.
- Well, we've got
the napalm spider,
the defoliant spider,
and mint.
- All right,
but can't you make it
just a little bit better?
( APPLAUSE )
Come on, everybody,
back me up here.
- Come on, Joel.
Joel, we're businessmen.
- All right, all right,
all right,
I'll tell you
what we're going to do,
since you're
a friend of ours.
We're going to throw in--
well, grab that tray down there,
will you?
- Get the tray.
- My arms are inoperable,
so I can't grab it.
- He's grabbing the tray.
There we go.
- Okay, this right here,
is this what
we're talking about?
- Now, this, this--
- Looks like
a really big spider.
- Oh, that's the granddaddy
of all explosive spiders, Joel.
This one can take out
a whole city block.
Now, where's that disk, Crow?
- Well, Servo,
the amazing thing is
I've slipped that lightweight
disk into Joel's pocket.
- And this rocket
really is comfortable.
I'll take it.
- Ha.
- I like this phantom creep bit.
Reagan's deregulation
of television really pays off.
- If you've got
your charge card out,
I'd like to get the,
uh, Snackmaster thing.
- Well, as you know, Joel,
the torture
never stops around here.
That's what you get from
hanging out with guys like us--
one more bad film.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no,
don't pass out on me now.
Go ahead,
put in the tape, Frank.
Taste my steel,
pasty boy, after this.
( THEME MUSIC PLAYING )
( MUSIC PLAYING )
- Oh, boy.
- Robert L. Lippert.
- Armida, is that Spanish?
- Spanish Armida?
- Look, Smoki Whitefish--
sounds delicious.
- Hm, Fred Colby,
the cheese magnate.
Rudy Robles.
- Zach Williams
as Sami and Chief Zabu.
- Norman Cerf,
the best editor to come out
of the agrarian feudal
collective system.
- Hm, I'll have a Carl Berger.
- All right.
- Original song, "    There's
No One In My Heart But Me.".
- By Dr. Christian Barnard.
- Hm, Jo Pagano,
based on a pasta dish.
- Jo Pagano was based on
an idea by William Stephens?
- That's Rum Collins'
smarter brother.
- Hm.
- Mars, extending us a welcome.
- Hey, look, a Shriner.
I don't remember the name,
but the fez is familiar.
- So, anyway,
I'm flying one of those
new flying carpets they've got,
and it's great.
- Enjoy the only exterior shot.
- Portugee Joe's.
Ha, they've got the west
grass skirt night.
Enjoy the fentoozler
and keep the cup.
- Uh, Donner,
party of three, please.
- ♪ That summer night
I chanced to pass you by ♪
- Mm-hm.
- ♪ I smiled at you ♪
- ♪ They smiled at you ♪
- ♪ He smiled at me ♪
- ♪ We all smiled
At each other ♪
- ♪ We smiled ♪
- ♪ Ba-bum ♪
- You know, that piano player
is not bad-- and the girl.
I'll probably get her.
Dig it.
- ♪ You possess me
so completely ♪
- Mm-hm.
- Uh, excuse me.
Are you our waitress?
I'd like to order whatever
is on the wall over there.
- ♪ There's no one in my life ♪
- Table dancing!
Table dance!
- Whoa, whoa.
- Hey!
- ♪ In your arms ♪
- Uh, she must be enforcing
the two-drink minimum, I guess.
- We'd like our check.
- ♪ Don't want to
But I do ♪
- We've got to stop bringing
our business lunches here.
- Let me put my eye in.
What, what is that you say?
What? I can't hear you.
Hm?
Oh.
- Uh, do you think
I could get a table
in the no singing section?
Is that possible?
- ♪ Or familiar ♪
- Olive.
- So, I was saying
to Brutus the other day--
- ♪ Sharing so patiently ♪
( MIKE AND BOTS COUGHING )
♪ And when you return ♪
- So, which navy is he in?
- Uh, I think
he's a cab driver. Oh.
- ♪ I'll burn your lips
with kisses ♪
- Burn your lips?
- Saigon,
I'm still in Saigon.
- ♪ There's no one in my heart
But you ♪
- ♪ And heartburn ♪
( APPLAUSE )
- Freebird!
- Whipping post,
whipping post! Woo!
- I was waiting for
three hours last night.
- I did not tell you
I would be there.
- It's a really long song.
- Your eyes said you would.
- Aw, but my lips did not.
- My dress said maybe,
but my patella
gave a resounding yes.
- You're sweet,
but dangerous, Mr. Simpson.
- Good, then
I'm making progress.
- Hm.
- Incidentally, Yvonne,
let's stop being so formal.
The name is Bob.
- When I stop being formal,
then it will be
dangerous for you.
- Oh!
- Aha, check please.
- I'll give you five minutes.
- For what?
- To start running.
- To have another drink.
- Oh, our boyfriend's here.
- I think you have company,
Mr. Simpson.
- And his hat
is more authentic.
- Say, did you take my red
underwear with the big S on it?
- I thought
I'd find you in here.
Do you realize we're supposed to
take off in 20 minutes?
- Easy, son, easy.
Have a drink.
- We haven't got time.
- We don't fly for Northwest.
- What do you mean
we don't have time?
We've got all the time
in the world.
- Oh, I hate
when he says that.
- Take a look at that.
- Hm, look here,
two more pilots arrested.
- Hm, "Famous tennis star
becomes woman complete."
- Hm, ordained minister.
- Will of Peter Vanderhorn,
multimillionaire diamond tycoon,
was probated yesterday.
- Hm, sounds painful.
- Provided for reward
of 5,000 pounds sterling
for the discovery of his
daughter, Greta, dead or alive.
She was returning home
by plane
from an American finishing
school, the first day--
- Oh, no, no, no. When you
read it, do all the voices.
- Last communication
from the navigator
placed the plane somewhere over
the Zambezi territory.
No word of the plane
or any of the passengers
has ever been received.
- Reading my horoscope.
- Well, so what?
Our business is flying
private passengers;
and I don't want
to remind you, son,
but two of them are
waiting for us right now.
- Know what?
Right now,
we're out of business.
- Ssss-- ow!
- Oh!
- Ow.
- Oh, oh!
- Look, Mike, sit down.
- I am sitting.
- There's 5,000 pounds
reward there,
which is about $20,000,
for anyone who finds
Greta Vanderhorn,
and she doesn't
have to be alive.
- You are whacky.
- I'm nutty.
I'm JC Finklehoffer.
- What's been lost
can be found.
- If that were so,
the plane would've been found
a long time ago.
- But they weren't able to
send out search planes
while the war was on.
Now that restrictions
have been lifted,
every broken down flyer
on the African coast
will be taking off to look for
the wreckage of that plane,
and we're going to
get there first.
- Who said anything about
getting there at all?
- I did.
- Yeah, he did.
- Yeah, I heard him.
- I hate to remind you, son,
but you're only the junior
partner in this concern.
- I know, Dad.
- I happen to own three-quarters
of that crate, remember?
- Uh, just as if you'd ever
let me forget it.
- Then, come on, Mike.
Time is of the essence.
- Yeah, yeah, I know,
just like your old ballet
teacher used to tell you.
- Oh, I deserved that--
good one.
- We've got to load on
some extra tanks of gas.
I think a little trip
in the jungle will do you good.
- Oh, I went
before we got here.
- Uh, he's with me.
Excuse us.
- There's a man
on the wing of the plane!
- Ah!
- What's a five-letter word
for rum and Diet Pepsi?
- We should hit
Zambezi territory by morning.
- Says you.
- Is that your hand?
Hm.
- I think we just flew
through a dissolve.
- Oh.
Wow, say, these View-Masters
really bring nature to life.
Look at that.
That's irr-elephant.
- Hey, I see us up there.
- Okay, boy scout,
how much longer
do you intend to spend
on your good deed?
- Now, I was
in the ballet division.
- It will be a good deed,
if we collect the reward.
- If we collect it.
- You mean those cookies?
- Looking for that wreckage
is going to be like
looking for a needle
in a haystack,
to coin a phrase.
- Is that yours?
- You go on and coin one,
and if it'll make you feel
any better.
- Nothing's going to make me
feel any better
until we're out of this.
Come on, Bob--
- Ah, come clean with me, Frank.
Tell me
you haven't had the urge
to ram this baby
into the ground.
- Hey, a petting zoo.
Now we're at the dells.
( THEME MUSIC PLAYING )
- Mike!
- Hm?
- Mike, I think I see something!
Here, take a look.
- Hmph, yeah, that's neat.
Hey, pop in another slide
for me, will you?
- Yeah, could be.
- Well, let's go down
and see.
- Okay.
- Hey, turn back!
We're over Nebraska!
- Did ancient astronauts
land here
millions of years ago?
- Bill, not a crash landing!
- No!
( MIKE AND BOTS SHOUTING )
- Horses and zebra.
- Well, they had to land.
The rubber band is unwound.
- You go ahead, Bob.
You're the boy scout.
Ballet division.
- Look, a tiger!
- What, in Africa?
- Shhh!
- Hey, don't step
in the macumba.
- Nice ensembles
for a couple of guys
who can't remember
to gas up.
- Now, how do you run this?
- How far away did you say
the wreckage is?
- Uh, that's kind of personal.
- Oh, about a mile.
- North by northeast, right?
- Mm, that was a good movie.
- Keep your eyes peeled, Bob.
Remember, we're not
on the Rue de la Paix.
- I'll go one better.
I'll take them clean
out of my sockets,
if you'd like.
- Yeah.
( GROWLING )
- Hello, kitty cat.
- Breath mint?
- Springtime,
when a young man's fancies
likely turn to
thoughts of elephants.
- Hi, I'm Satan.
Enjoy the film.
- You're wondering
how we can dominate this,
aren't you, Mike?
- Pretty nosy, kitty cat.
( GROWLING )
- Hm,
it looks like they all
just got out of the shower.
- Yeah, and they're
on a snipe hunt.
- Who's got the bag?
- Hm.
They're on the same set
at least.
They're all springtime fresh,
though.
They're on a collision course
with a whole lot of trouble.
- No, I can't find
your ball anywhere.
What are you playing,
a Schlesinger 5?
- I think this hole
breaks to the left.
- Did you hear something, Mike?
- Yeah.
- Wait a minute, Bob!
( GUNSHOT )
- Oh!
- I hope that's
an acceptable greeting.
- Oops.
- Oh, sorry, sorry, everyone.
- Please, let's not bicker
over who shot who.
The important thing is that
we realize we made a mistake.
Hm, good rifling.
- Feels good in hand.
- This will be killing,
good killing stick.
- Carbine, nice action.
- You can't make me.
You can't make me!
( SERVO HUMMING TUNE FROM
"GILLIGAN'S ISLAND" )
- Hey, it's Ginger and Maryann.
- Hm.
- Mata Greta is beautiful.
Mata Greta hair,
very beautiful.
- Hey, look, stop kissing
up to me, okay?
- Wanama, did you study
your spelling last night?
- Uh, dog ate it.
- Oh, yes, yes.
- Good.
Then let me hear you spell,
uh, beautiful.
- Let me hear you spell
patronize.
- Beautiful.
- Will this be on the final?
- Ah, yes, beautiful.
- S-l--
- That's B--
- A--
- E--
- B--
- A--
- E--
- U--
- R-Y.
- Hm?
- T-I-F-U-L.
( LAUGHTER )
- That is wonderful.
- Okay, now spell
antidisestablishmentarianism.
- I, uh, think--
- Think.
- Stink?
- What is this,
a Dr. Seuss book? Think!
- Beautiful,
more beautiful word of all.
( LAUGHTER )
- Hair like
my best friend of all.
- Thanks for playing.
Sam, where's Quincy?
( SPEAKING IN NATIVE LANGUAGE )
- Uh, could you spell that,
please?
( SPEAKING IN NATIVE LANGUAGE )
- Uh, second word.
- Is it a film?
- Sounds like, uh--
- Play.
- How do you like that?
- I don't.
- Mm-hm.
- Doma.
- Look, don't tell them
that we're white.
- I didn't say Simon Says.
- Okay, Simon Says.
- Miss Vanderhorn, I presume.
- Oh, funny.
- You are not to speak
until you have been spoken to.
- Say, what is this?
We know who you are.
You may have these natives
buffaloed, but--
- Silence!
- Ooh.
- Or perhaps you wish me
to turn you over to my subjects.
- What, spelling?
- French?
- Trey?
- Did you hear that, Mike?
- Social studies?
- Subjects.
- Shut up, Bob. You've got us
in enough of a jam as it is.
- Nugara.
- What'd you call me?
I, I'm, I'm first native.
- What happened, Nugara?
- White devil kill Zulu.
- Fractured speech.
- Make fire from long stick.
- Loose articles.
- Big noise.
Zulu dead.
( SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE )
- Ah, sorry,
wrong, wrong scene.
Uh, excuse me, pardon me.
I'll just step out.
- You shot Zulu?
- Oh, well, we didn't
actually get his name.
- How was I to know?
He came bouncing out
of the jungle with that spear,
and I--
but I don't get this.
We came here to find you.
Maybe we made a mistake.
- Maybe you did.
- A big one.
- Certainly, it was a mistake
when you killed Zulu
without justification.
Neither he nor any of the others
would have harmed you.
They would have
treated you like gods,
which they thought you were.
- But I still don't get it.
What do you care
what happened to that native?
- I care very much.
- Doh!
- I would suggest
that you be silent.
The penalty for murder is
the same here as anywhere else.
- Yeah, a plea bargain
to a suspended sentence.
( SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE )
- Uh, not yet.
Uh, two more pages.
Yeah, just, uh, step back.
( SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE )
( MIKE AND BOTS REPEATING )
- Uh, maybe you wouldn't
mind telling me
exactly what goes on
around here.
- Well, we have activities,
craft making.
- A trial
will be conducted tonight
to determine the innocence
or guilt of you and your friend.
- And now--
- Now, now.
- Yeah, now it's your turn.
- Let it out, man, yep.
Sing, baby, yeah.
- Morty Gunty
appearing this weekend.
( DRUMS )
- And now,
ladies and gentlemen,
the Tropicanda extends
a warm Las Vegas welcome
to Mr. Gene Krupa!
- Go, Gene, go.
- Go.
- Mata rules land.
Mata ruler.
- I now pronounce you
man and, uh, man.
- Huh?
- My people have reached
a verdict.
- You're to be extradited.
- Since you had no part
in the murder of Zulu,
and in fact tried to
prevent further violence--
- You'll be deep fried.
- You'll be permitted to return
to your plane safely.
- That's nice.
When?
- As soon as your friend's
sentence has been carried out.
- What do you mean,
my sentence?
- It is the will of my people
that you be executed
on the first full moon.
- Hm.
- Which will be
eight nights from tonight.
- Oh, that sounds fair,
but-- huh?
- But you can't--
- Easy, Bob.
- Your sentence
has been pronounced. -
- Look, Bob,
we'll appeal.
- Just to be sure that
you do not attempt to escape,
you will both remain guarded
until the execution.
- Wow, we're already
pretty guarded.
( SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE )
- Mata baru.
- Yeah, yeah, mata baru.
- Mata baru!
- Okay, get on with it.
- Sheez.
- Boy, she really put the boot
to you back there, Bob.
- I suppose we've got to tip.
I hate cops.
- Had to get the hanging judge.
- Well, I've been in
better jails in my life.
- That's nothing
to brag about, Bob.
- You've got it over me--
first one I was ever in;
and from the looks of things,
it's liable to be the last.
- Yeah, well, what are you
worried about?
They're not gonna execute you.
I'm the one that got
the death sentence.
How do you like that Greta
giving us the business?
- You're right.
I feel great.
- The dame's gone native.
- Don't squawk to me, Bob.
( MIKE AND BOTS SQUAWKING )
It was your own idea,
remember,
coming out here
to look for her.
We were doing all right
ferrying private passengers
until you decided
that there were easier ways
to make a living.
Boy, do I wish I was in
Portugee Joe's bar right now--
- Maybe they've got
a microbrewery around.
- --hoisting up a long,
tall, cold one.
- Yeah, well,
maybe we will yet.
- Put that away.
- All right, all right.
I'm not gonna use it
unless I have to.
- It's a lighter.
- I also managed to
hang onto our hand compass.
- Oh, good.
- Good.
- You're not gonna let me down,
are you, Mike?
- Don't worry.
We've got eight days
to figure a way out of this.
- We're in this together,
and we'll get out of it
together.
- But I'm the one
that shot that native,
and I'm the one
they're gonna execute.
- Relax, will you?
Like I said,
we're in this together.
- Just kidding.
( SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE )
Uh, never mind.
- Mata Greta
wants talk with you.
No you.
- Here, have this.
I've gotta go
with Henry Silva here.
- Give my love to Mata Greta.
- Say, I wonder what Mata means.
- Hey, you've got a smart mouth.
- We've gotta split.
- Yeah.
- Mata means white goddess.
- Whoa.
- White goddess.
( THEME MUSIC PLAYING )
- Hey, Joel,
so what's the deal
with those magic binocular
things we've been seeing?
- Oh, that's an old
cinematic device that,
uh, filmmakers of old
used to use
to kind of teach the viewer
that they were looking
through binoculars,
even though if you really look
it looks just like
a movie screen.
- And, uh, so then
they just run totally unrelated
stock footage of animals, right,
and not even
at the same altitude.
- Or creatures not even
indigenous to the area.
- Yeah, right.
In fact, Cambot came all
set up with such things.
They're called gobos,
if you want to see them.
Gobos are matte box effects
for film.
Okay, you want to try it?
- Well, so we'll just sit here
and act as the brunt
of your little visual joke?
- Yeah, that's right.
- Okay.
- Something like that.
Okay, this one is called
the binocular scope.
- Hey, get us.
We're a piece of
stock footage.
- All right, and this one
is the keyhole scope.
- You know, you're the only man
for me, Servo.
- Oh, Crow.
- All right, this is the--
- Oh. ( MAKING KISSING SOUNDS )
- --high-powered scope, scope.
- And so the French
prime minister
shall receive the quarter--
look out, look out!
Oh, Sacre Bleu!
- Okay, this is
the periscope scope.
- I don't care how you do it.
You must sink the Bismark.
- And also the driving
Miss Daisy scope.
- We might as well be walking
as driving this slow,
Miss Daisy.
- Just watch
where you're going.
- Okay, this here
is the, uh, microscope.
- Uh, go ahead, Crow.
You can imitate a one-celled
animal better than I can.
- I am an ameba.
- Starting to look a bit more
like the Sammy Davis, Jr. scope.
- Oh, yeah.
- Okay, this is the--
- The candy man.
- This is the Lucy scope.
- Ah, Ricky!
- Ah.
- Turns out
I was never funny.
- Okay, the small intestine
scope.
- Ooh, I feel so funky.
I need soothing and coating.
- That's what we feel like.
- This is the, uh,
Jose Feliciano scope there.
CROWChico,
don't get discouraged.
- All right, this is
the Family Circus scope.
- Okay, who broke my vase?
- Not me.
- Okay, followed by
the jack-o-lantern scope.
- Huh?
- The, uh, glaucoma scope.
- What?
- And if you want to get
really fancy,
you add the Family Circus scope
with the glaucoma scope
and get the Hubble scope.
Okay, there's that, all right,
followed by the Pope scope.
- What?
- The scopes
monkey trial scope,
otherwise known as
inherit the window-rama.
- Huh?
- The ever popular nope scope.
- Oh, brother.
- Oh, come on.
- Like that.
And finally movie sign-o-scope.
( BUZZER )
- Oh, movie sign!
( SHOUTING )
- Leave us alone, Nugara.
- Well, that binocular
syncs pretty good.
- That's really cool.
- Yeah, Cambot had
something like that.
- Come here.
- Spread out, Sabu.
Three's a crowd.
- Sit down.
- Can I order right away?
I'm really famished.
- The coast is clear.
- Did my father send you
to find me?
- Well, not exactly,
Miss Vanderhorn.
- What do you mean,
not exactly?
- Your father's dead.
- And my mom?
- Oops.
- When did he die?
- Not quite a month ago.
- My partner shot him, too.
- Well, I guess
you can throw that away.
- Oh, it just came
with the frame.
Queer-looking old duck.
- Never lived to find out
what happened to me.
- Oh.
- Exactly what did happen?
- Okay, here goes.
I was paging through
the dailies,
and I see an opening
for a jungle goddess.
- I was a student
in college for girls,
at Hastings on the Hudson.
- Meanwhile, at stately
Wayne Manor--
Miss Harcourt's
School for Girls.
GRETA:  It was Sunday morning.
- Chicks on beds.
GRETA:
September 1, 1939.
I was listening
to the radio
with my roommate,
Helen Philips.
VOICE ON RADIO:  In general, the
world picture remains the same.
Although the threat of war is--
- She had a really deep voice.
VOICE ON RADIO:  One moment,
please, ladies and gentlemen.
I've just been handed
a teletype.
Prime Minister
Neville Chamberlain
has just addressed Parliament,
and I quote his exact words,
quote--
- Help!
VOICE ON RADIO: I am
( indistinct ) to inform you
that unless the German
government suspends
all aggressive actions
against Poland
not later than 11:00 a.m.
British summer time,
September 3rd,
His Majesty's government will,
without hesitation,
fulfill its obligations
to Poland.
Unquote.
- Well, that's good, Helen.
Now try opening with a joke.
- What are you doing
that for, Greta?
- I don't want to hear anymore.
Do you realize this means war?
- Those morning zoo guys
just grate on me.
- So what?
This is the United States,
remember?
Who cares what's going on
in Europe?
- I'm rich
with no political standing.
- I'm sorry, Greta.
I forgot you're Dutch.
- Oh, that's all right.
I'll have to see
Miss Harcourt.
- What are you going to do?
- I'm going to take
the first plane home,
if I can make reservations.
- But why?
You're safe here.
- That's beside the point.
I don't want to be stuck here
for the duration.
And if the war breaks,
well, maybe I'll be a nurse.
My first aid course
might come in handy.
- Oh, it sounds like
a lot of kooky fun.
We'll put on a show;
and once the B2
turns into guava jelly,
I'll still be alive.
- Johannesburg
is in a British dominion.
If war breaks, well,
I, I want to be with my father.
- Averell Harriman?
- It's Adolphe Menjou.
- Yeah, I think so.
Boris Karloff?
GRETA:
After considerable red tape ,
I was able to catch a plane
for Lisbon.
- We went on some bombing raids
over central Europe.
- We took the most direct route
to South Africa.
It was not easy
to make arrangements
to continue my journey.
- Hm, it's a mobile home.
- The war had brought
a great deal of confusion.
- Filled with La-Z Boys.
- Plane reservations
were scarce;
however,
I was finally successful
and was able to board
another plane for Johannesburg.
At last, I was on my way
to join my father.
- We're on our way!
- In order to reach
Johannesburg,
it was necessary to fly
over the dense African jungle.
- And do a lot of
voiceover work.
- I was engaged
in a conversation
with a very lovely woman.
- That I didn't like.
- Of course, they will be called
( indistinct ) first.
- Uh-huh.
- Seems so strange.
Their father was killed
in the last war.
- That's great.
- Yeah, that's great.
Now put a sock in it,
will you, granny?
- ( indistinct )
Oh, when you've lived
as long as I have, child,
you'll find
it never pays to worry.
I used to worry terribly
about everything.
Little things
and big things.
- Orange things
and paisley things.
- What on earth
is the matter with you?
We all--
- Yeah, sure.
Hey, my skull's
starting to hurt.
Could you clam up?
- Hey, what is this,
the airplane of Dr. Caligari?
- Uh, the captain and I
are out of drinks.
- Ladies and gentlemen,
we've just received word
over the wireless
that His Majesty's government
has declared war on Germany.
- So, it's happy hour
until we land!
( CHEERING )
- We shall make every attempt
to reach Johannesburg
as per schedule.
- That ought to hold them.
- Well, it's come.
- May the Lord have mercy
on us all.
- Oh, I think He does,
except for you.
- Stop her!
She's got a gun!
- She's got a gun!
- Look out!
- I think you'll all
want to join me.
- ♪ It's a dance of death death
It's a dance of death ♪
- ♪ God save the queen. ♪
- I figured on seeing Betty
and the kids for Christmas.
- What about your wife?
- I wonder how long
it'll be now.
At least I can send him
a picture of his dad
in an RAF uniform.
- Instead of that darned dress.
- Meanwhile
in yet another plane--
- Uh-oh.
Uh, when you stopped for fuel,
did you-- huh?
- Uh, we're in trouble.
How's the model doing?
- Not too good.
- Uh, when you were
in flight school,
did they teach you
how to scream?
- So, you want to tell them
or should I?
Uh-oh.
- She's dropping fast.
I'd better go
warn the passengers
to fasten
their safety belts.
- Yeah, like
that's gonna help.
- Airport 42.
- Uh, Steve,
uh, never mind.
I've got it.
Oh, kind of my fault, sorry.
Sorry.
GRETABy some miracle,
I was the only survivor.
- By some plot contrivance.
GRETAWhen I came to,
it was morning.
I didn't know where I was
or how I was going to get help.
- Thanks to my Halston,
I still looked fabulous!
GRETA:  I started wandering
through the jungle,
trying to get back
to civilization.
- I found that travel
really broadens you.
I met neat people
like Roddy McDowall;
and, you know,
it's really true what they say.
Ooh, that monkey
gave me such a chill.
- Well, you know what I think
what this forest needs
is a woman's touch.
There I was, surrounded
by salad fixings for miles
and no mandarin orange
vinaigrette in sight.
- Hey, toots,
it's me, Satan.
Catch you later, you know?
- Suddenly, there I was
in front of
a rear projection screen.
You know
how I hate those.
( GROWLS )
( SCREAMS )
- I screamed, and that seemed
to help our relationship.
- Oh, darn.
Oh, what a bad time
to break a heel.
- Then I came upon
a sanitary landfill.
I knew civilization
must be near.
GRETA:  It wasn't long after
I started through the jungle
that I was confronted
by a group of natives.
I was really frightened then.
- Uh, you can't tell
from this shot, but I was.
GRETA:  But suddenly
they started to kneel
in an attitude of worship.
I didn't know why,
but I felt safer.
So, mustering my courage--
- I began kicking them
repeatedly.
-  Take me to your village.
- Huh?
- Did you get that?
- Hm?
- Take me to your village.
- Hm.
- She thinks we speak English.
- Hey, sister,
don't give me any crap.
-  You take me--
- Me take you--
- Your village, village.
- Oh, you want us to take you
to our village, oh.
- Ah.
- Mm, I'm perplexed but charmed
by this plucky stranger.
- We eat tonight.
- Upsy-daisy.
( SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE )
- Rhubarb, rhubarb, rhubarb.
( SPEAKING GIBBERISH )
- What's going on?
Somebody drop a contact?
- Here, let me help you.
( SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE )
- You really caught us
at a bad time.
All of our suits
are out at the cleaners,
and it gets kind of
randy around here
when all the women
are away, you understand.
( SPEAKING IN NATIVE LANGUAGE )
- Well, here's the first
problem.
She's covered with fur.
Get me a razor.
RETA:  She was a very sick girl;
and only then did I realize
that they wanted me
to help her.
- I stared at her;
that seemed to help.
- Does this story
have a point?
- When Wanama recovered,
the natives were sure
that I was a goddess.
When Chief M'benga died,
Oolonga,
the witch doctor,
tried to poison the natives
against me,
but he wasn't successful.
- Well, do they still believe
that you're a goddess?
- Oh, that's another
flashback.
- If they thought
I was deceiving them,
Oolonga the witch doctor
would make short work of me.
- Aha, I'm beginning to
get all this now.
- Good.
- But why did you have Bob
sentenced to death?
- You don't think
I intended to
carry that sentence out,
do you?
- We did.
- I was counting on it.
- I was only
stalling for time.
-     Smart girl.
- You little minx.
- I sort of figured that you
were just putting on an act.
- I had to do it.
If the natives thought
otherwise, we'd all be dead.
- Well, that gives us
just seven days
to get out of here.
- Your plane,
is it all right?
- Oh, it's terrific.
- Yes, in a little clearing
about a mile from where
your plane crashed.
- Yeah, must be
the accident zone.
- Trust me.
Obey my every command,
no matter how strange
it might seem.
- Oh, wow.
- I'll find a way for
the three of us to escape,
though I'm not so sure
your friend deserves it.
I don't like him.
- Oh, Bob's all right--
a little trigger happy,
perhaps, but he's all right.
- I don't like him.
- Oh, Bob's all right--
a little trigger happy.
( BEATING DRUMS )
- What is that?
- Must be the late show.
- Now, would it be
crass of me
to say the natives
are restless?
- It's the dance of death.
- Oh, well, that's cute.
- Not so cute.
Oolonga's working the natives up
into a frenzy.
-  What's the snake for?
- Nastassja Kinski.
- The snake is Oolonga's
pet executioner.
- You mean he--
- It's a very torturous death.
The poison works very slowly,
and it's horrible.
- Kind of sounds like
the plot of this movie.
- Tommy Tune
and Morris Cunningham.
- I think you'd better go now.
We don't want to arouse
any suspicion.
- Speak for yourself.
- I'll see you again tomorrow.
There's so much I want to
talk to you about--
everything that's happened
in the last six years.
- It must've taken
a great deal of courage
to stick this out
for six years.
- Hm.
- Goodnight, white goddess.
- Goodnight.
And don't worry.
Nugara!
- Uh, is the courtesy van ready?
- Nugara, take this man back;
but, remember,
no harm must come
to either of them.
We must fulfill the law.
- Yes, Mata Greta.
- Kill him, kill him!
- I can't believe
he went for it-- chump.
- Now, Calgon, take me away!
( BEATING DRUMS )
- They say
it's never a rock video
until they burn something.
( MIKE AND BOTS
DOING NATIVE CHANT )
Catchy tune, isn't it?
- Maybe that snake
probably had it.
- What's going on out there?
- Seems like the witch doctor
is having a little party.
- Uh, am I invited?
- Some party.
- It's the dance of death.
- Well, could you tell them
to turn the bass down?
I can't sleep.
- That was incredible.
- Was I dreaming,
or was there a dance of death
going on last night?
- She liked the color
of my eyes better.
- She must like something.
- What do you mean
by that crack?
- How do I know you two aren't
cooking up something together?
- Oh, you know I can't cook.
- Meaning what?
- Meaning there's
5,000 pounds reward
for little Mata Greta.
If you two
get out of here alone,
you won't have to
split the reward with me.
- Hey, good idea!
- I ought to crush your skull!
- Ah, it's been crushed.
I'm sorry, Mike, I'm sorry.
This place is giving me
the heebee-jeebees.
- Oh, and I thought
they sprayed.
- --if I don't get out of here.
- Yeah, yeah, I guess I know
how you feel.
But like I said, we'll
get out of this together.
- Oh, good, my clams casino.
-  Mata Greta said--
- Charge it to the room.
- --you come eat with her now.
- Oh, thank you.
- All right.
- Well, that's my date.
I'll see you later.
- So long, sucker.
- This for you.
- Yeah.
- How about you and I
cooking up something ourselves,
good looking?
- Hey, there's
an Inuit pole out here.
- Different strokes,
you know?
- Hello.
- How.
- Tell me, where are
all your subjects headed for?
- They're going out
after wild antelope.
They leave early so that they
can be back before dark.
They don't like
the jungle at night.
- But I do.
- Oh, won't you sit down?
- Well, thank you,
white goddess.
- Thank you, white racist.
- It's been a long time
since anyone called me Greta.
- All right, Greta.
- Hey, buttermilk biscuits.
-     Well, how does it look?
- Cheapo.
- Oh, well, tell me
what it is first.
- Oh, it isn't
what you might think.
I assure you that the natives
here are not cannibals.
- The Scottish call it haggis.
Well, that's a relief.
Did you cook it yourself?
- Goddesses don't cook.
What I wouldn't give
for a hamburger
and some nice
French fried potatoes.
- Mm-hm.
- That's right.
You went to school
in the States, didn't you?
- Mm-hm.
You're an American,
aren't you?
- Mm-hm.
I'm from Colorado.
And speaking of hamburgers,
I could go for one myself.
You see, I haven't been home
in three years.
Greta, do you mind
if we start right in?
I'm so hungry,
I could eat a horse.
- Hey, you're in luck!
- Sure.
- Huh?
- Don't worry.
Here, they call it zebra.
It's not only edible,
but, uh, quite delicious.
-  All right, if you say so.
- Hm, dark and white meat.
- Very tasty.
- Oh, white devil on fire!
- Oh, no, wait, wait, wait.
- No, uh, white devil
just having a Kent.
- Not quite yet.
- You're not from
around here, are you?
- Hey, you speak
pretty good English.
- Oh, sure, Mata Greta
teach me everything.
- Sure, you got money GI Joe?
- Me very smart.
- Did Mata Greta
tell you that, too?
- Oh, sure.
She no tell me
what smart means.
- Uh, means you're stacked.
-  You tell Wanama.
- Well, it, uh--
- Um.
- --means sort of like a--
- Oh, it's just different,
that's all!
- Dumb.
Very beautiful, dumb.
- Thought you'd like it.
Now get out of here!
- You eat now.
- You still here?
- Why everybody says
you white devil?
- Because I kill
indiscriminately.
You're very, very nice.
- Get me.
Sentenced to death,
and I'm still making time.
Yeah, I'm pretty cool.
- Don't nobody move.
- It's hard to believe
that the war lasted so long.
- If it hadn't been
for the atomic bomb--
tell me, Greta.
Didn't you ever
try to get out of here?
- I used to dream
my way out, Mike.
- I would take the magic trolley
or click my heels together.
- I used to dream about home
every night.
MIKE:     And after that?
- Oh, I gave up dreaming.
It was hopeless to try
and penetrate the jungle.
- Hm.
- I used to have the natives
take me out
on what you might call
hunting expeditions,
but they led nowhere.
- Then I just had a hamburger
with some French fried potatoes.
GRETA:
I know.
And my only hold on them
depends on their belief
that I'm a goddess.
- And so Leona Helmsley's
empire was built.
- --if we're to get
out of here alive.
- You must tell Bob
not to make any false moves.
- Like killing people.
GRETA:  He's got to be patient
until tomorrow morning.
- Are you sure
you can trust Wanama?
GRETAWanama would do
anything for me.
- Wanama's phenomenal.
- She's the only one I can trust
to lead us out of the jungle.
- Bob has a hand compass.
- And some
French fried potatoes.
- That will come in handy, too,
in case anything goes wrong.
I, uh, think
you'd better leave now.
- You always say
something like that
just when I'm
beginning to enjoy myself.
- Then I've gotta wait a few
minutes before I can leave.
- It's best.
- Well, that's life.
Here, what is this?
Where'd you get this?
- Wanama made it for me.
- Hm, world's greatest grandma.
- Hey, where did Wanama
get the stuff
she carved this from?
- On the outskirts
of the village.
Why?
- Why?
- Wanama's working through
a lot of pain, isn't she?
- Do you know what this is?
No, I guess you don't.
I saw something
just like this in Colorado.
- Well, what is it?
- Unless I'm crazy,
it's chronatite.
Of course, that wouldn't mean
anything to you, either.
Chronatite
is stuff that they use
in the manufacture
of atomic energy.
- Saps all your power,
if you're a visitor
from a foreign planet.
- Are you serious?
- Of course, I'm serious.
- Look, Bob knows a lot
about this kind of thing.
Do you mind
if I show it to him?
- Not if you want to.
- Yeah, you can take
target practice on it.
- If it is chronatite,
we'll organize
our own expedition
and come back for it.
- Provided we get
out of here alive, Mike.
- ♪ Wa-wa-wa-wa-wa ♪
( THEME MUSIC PLAYING )
- Hm, tastes like grandpa.
It's chronatite all right.
- You sure?
- I'd stake my life on it.
- That's already
in the kitty, Bob.
- I don't know
what it means to you,
but personally I've had my eye
on a ranch in Colorado
ever since I was a kid.
- Hm.
- Oh, yeah, like I care.
- Nugara is still on guard.
Our best chance is to make
a break for it just before dawn.
- Oh, wait a minute.
Greta's worked out
a plan for us.
- Hey, when did you start
calling her Greta?
- She told me
to call her goddess.
- There's no
getting through that jungle
without being slowed down
by a dame.
- Well, if we get through--
and I doubt very much
if we can--
Oolonga would be a cinch
to blame her.
Have you ever
stopped to think
what those natives
might do to her?
- Oh, yeah.
- So what?
That's her lookout.
She's the white goddess.
She can figure
a way out of this.
- Supposed they kill her?
- We don't have to
bring her back alive
to collect the reward.
And besides,
that's peanuts
alongside what
we'll collect on this.
- Hey, your horns
are showing, Bob.
- Where are you going?
- I'm taking this back to Greta.
Bob, I'm going to be kind
to you.
- I'm going to put you to sleep.
- The spot you're on
has twisted your mind.
Nobody can be
that much of a heel!
- But I can.
- I can; really, I can.
- Sure, you can.
- No, I can, really.
- I am a heel.
- How about a heel like he is?
- Why are they looking at me?
Get that camera off of me.
- I'm a heel.
- We'll be back
right after this.
- I'm still a heel.
- Such a heel.
- I appreciate the fact
that I can't leave this hole,
but is there any reason
why I can't have some water?
- Water?
- If it isn't
too much trouble.
- Wanama.
Bring white devil water.
- Water.
- Yeah, bring a lot of it,
and don't forget the ice.
- Ice?
- Skip it.
- Skip it?
- And, Wanama, bring it inside.
- Inside?
- It's hotter than blazes
out here.
- Blazes?
- I've arranged to send
all the natives out
on hunting expeditions
early tomorrow morning.
That will enable us
to travel by daylight.
- What about Nugara?
- You'll have to tie him up,
but I don't want him hurt.
Understand?
- You mean
you don't trust him?
- Oh, I don't dare.
After all, he is a Zambezi.
These natives are very
peculiar and childlike.
- They don't even shoot things
they don't understand.
- even if he knew
what we were up to.
- Well, what makes you think
you can trust Wanama?
- Oh, I know I can.
After all, she's been
my constant companion
for six years.
- Tell me, Wanama.
You know the jungle
pretty well, don't you?
- Oh, I get around.
- Oh, sure.
- Are you really an astronaut?
- Me very dumb.
- I guess you are at that.
Did you ever wonder
where Mata Greta came from?
- Ah, she's a temp, right?
-  The gods sent Mata Greta.
- Is that what she told you?
- Oh, no, but me know.
Everybody know.
- You love Mata Greta
very much, don't you?
- Oh, sure.
Everybody love Mata Greta.
- Then you'd want to help her,
if she needed you,
wouldn't you?
-  Help Mata Greta?
- Come on, get to the point!
Cut to the chase!
( indistinct ) Mata Greta?
- It will,
if we don't help her.
- Okay, what about the rifles.
- I, uh, I had to
have them destroyed.
The natives thought
they were weapons of evil.
- Heh-heh, they're kind of cute,
so leave me.
( CHUCKLING )
- Yes, the jungle is infested
with wild animals.
- Ha, so am I?
- Well, if we should
get in a spot,
you can always exert
your powers, white goddess.
- Oh-ho, that's rich.
Kill him.
- Mike, do you think
you could get
Bob's revolver
away from him?
I don't trust him.
- No, he'd never give it up.
- Then we'll just have to
take our chances.
- Now, don't worry.
- I'm the man of steel,
stop bullets,
the whole nine yards.
- You know,
it would serve him right,
if we'd turn him over
to the tender mercies
of Oolonga the witch doctor.
- Here, here,
we couldn't do that.
- Let me just
patronize you a bit.
- You know, Mike, I think
you're absolutely right.
He's undoubtedly
become unbalanced
by all that's happened.
- Yeah, he's not thinking
as clearly
as when he shot that guy.
- We'll have to watch him
very closely.
- Relax, goddess, relax.
- What's the matter, Wanama?
- Yeah, kitten,
why the long face?
- Me want to talk
Mata Greta alone.
- That's all right.
You may speak.
He's our friend.
- He friend white devil, too.
Please, Mata Greta, Wanama
want to speak with you alone!
- What's the matter Wanama?
- I have a feeling
this concerns the both of us.
- Hm.
- What happened, Wanama?
Were you with white devil?
- Or should I get out
the anatomically correct doll?
- Are you afraid
to tell me what happened?
- No.
Please, me want to talk
Mata Greta alone.
- Mata Greta wants you
to speak now.
- Get on with it, please!
- White devil want me
take him through jungle.
- Alone?
- He say that way
we help Mata Greta,
but Wanama don't believe.
- You didn't tell him
you were coming here, did you?
- Oh, no.
Wanama, Wanama dumb.
- Wanama dumb--
doo-doo-doo-doo-doo.
Wanama dumb--
doo-doo-doo-doo.
- Be careful, Mike.
- So, did you do it?
- Mata Greta.
Mata Greta love him?
- Isn't there a magazine
devoted to this?
- Oh.
MIKE:
I'll take that, Bob.
- Are you daffy?
- No, I'm Porky.
You're Daffy.
Remember?
- I don't think so.
We're pulling out
tomorrow morning,
and Greta and I both decided
that it would be better
if I packed the artillery
on this little safari.
- Yeah, see?
- Oh, you and Greta decided,
did you?
Well, you go on back to Greta
and do some more deciding.
- Yeah, says you.
- This is my piece of iron,
and I'm going to keep it.
- Give me that.
- 1942!
- Man of steel, huh?
Phone this in to Perry White.
- Now I'm packing the rod.
- That's right.
- Get up, ooh,
off of the table, oh.
- Visitor from
another planet-- hey!
- Ugh.
- For being mortal man--
oh, you've got a little
on your chin there.
- Oh, I think you can--
- I don't want to do this.
- All this Pier One stuff
collapses.
Hey, look! They have
collapsing furniture.
- Looks so real.
- Bite you.
- Mata Greta!
( SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE )
Mata Greta,
- Gwano hit fan!
- Ooh.
- Oh!
- I will kill you!
I will kill him!
- Faster than a speeding-- oh.
- Yeah, right, more powerful
than a wimp.
( GUNSHOT )
- Oh, great, that's twice
in the same week.
- You fool.
- I didn't mean it, sweetie.
- I just winged him.
- It was an accident.
- Oh, great,
now he's got a line.
( SPEAKING IN NATIVE LANGUAGE )
- He's never gonna
like you now, Bill.
- Off to deliver more flowers.
- Nothing can stop Oolonga.
He's going after the hunters.
We'll have to start now
without Wanama,
before Oolonga
reaches the tribe.
- You're not gonna go
without me.
- We should leave you here,
but come on.
- Go to my place and wait.
- She's just gotta pack
a few things.
- Okay, Greta.
Come on.
- Come on, Junior.
Let's get off this picture.
Besides, I want to get home
and shoot holes in Gary.
Mata Greta.
( SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE )
- Greta give him
a new heart sac.
- No.
- Yeah, yeah,
bathe it in cool water,
put a poultice on it.
I've gotta beat cheeks.
- You take care of him
just as I've taught you.
Mata Greta must leave now.
They will take me back
where I came from.
Mata Greta
no come back to Wanama?
- I don't know.
You be a good girl, Wanama,
and remember everything
I've taught you.
- How to make
the scene darker?
- I'll remember everything
you've taught me.
- I've gotta blow.
See ya.
- Mata Greta.
- Nobody taught anybody to act.
- Hm.
- Skipper!
- Little buddy!
- Hey, Bob,
there's a living thing.
Why don't you swing
into high and kill it?
( CHUCKLING )
- Skipper!
- Little buddy!
- Hey, Bill,
when you were a kid,
and, uh, you got pets,
did you kill them?
And, hey, what did happen
to your sister, anyway?
- Mata Greta!
( SPEAKING IN NATIVE LANGUAGE )
( BEATING DRUM )
- Oh, no, no,
I didn't say start the band.
( SHOUTING )
- Hey, we eat tonight.
- Hey, you never saw
that tree before.
You want to kill it, Bob, huh?
- We've gotta get out of here.
- Why don't we just
set a whole torch--
torch the whole continent, Bob.
Would you like that, huh?
- The witch doctor
is gathering the tribe.
We'd better hurry!
( ALL SHOUTING )
- What in the same scratch
is that noise?
- Sounds like a mosquito
about the size of your head
just got sucked in
through the access ports.
- Oh, don't be absurd.
A mosquito couldn't live
in a vacuum.
Hey, there's a ship
coming into range.
- Hey, Cambot, give us
rocket number nine.
Let's see what it looks like.
- Hey, that's no mosquito.
The British stopped using those
at the end of the war.
- Hey, look,
something's coming in
on the Hexfield view screen.
( GUNSHOTS FROM TOY GUN )
- Would you stop that?
Stop it!
We're not sure
if we don't understand them yet.
- Sorry, sorry.
- Hey, what do you guys want?
- We want to shoot you.
( GUNSHOTS FROM TOY GUN )
- Stop that!
Stop it!
You can't shoot
through a view screen.
- Oh, sorry, sorry.
Let me.
Uh, hello, greetings,
insignificant life forms.
We come bearing gifts,
beads, trinkets,
Coke bottles,
accessories.
- And bullets.
( GUNSHOTS )
- Joel, what the heck
do they want?
- Actually, our needs
are rather simple.
I, uh, bought a little,
brought a little list.
Uh, uh, all we need is, uh--
ah, here it is--
mineral rights, women,
property, scalps,
food, clothing.
It's the standard list.
Oh, and also we want
the cute one's head,
if we could.
- Uh, that must be you, Joel.
- Yeah, definitely Joel.
- Hey, quiet, you guys.
We're talking to an alleged
higher life form,
whatever that means.
- That's us.
( GUNSHOTS )
- Right now, if you could just
pop that stuff over to our ship,
we'd greatly appreciate it.
Oh, I brought a little treat
for you, too.
Uh, the magic fire stick.
- Ooh.
- Also the ball in the cup
trick, uh--
- We also brought VD, smallpox,
and, uh, the widow maker.
( GUNSHOTS )
- Stop that, you idiot!
Now, Mr. Joel.
- Yeah?
- You are a white man with
strange-looking slave types.
Why haven't you
exploited them yet?
- Or at least shot them.
( GUNSHOTS )
- Hey, listen, you two.
These two slave types
happen to be my friends,
and I don't know
where you two get off
waltzing around
geosynchronous orbit
trying to throw your
white male weight around.
You've got another think coming.
You're messing with
the Satellite of Love.
- Yeah.
- I see.
Did you enjoy the taurine?
The radicchio
was picked fresh.
Kill them.
( GUNSHOTS )
- Oh, brother.
- I will kill them!
- Man, we've gotta stop
giving our address out.
- Yeah.
- You know that?
( THEME MUSIC PLAYING )
- Oh!
- Hold it.
What's the matter, Greta?
- I've twisted my ankle.
- Oh, come on.
Now, let me get this straight.
You survived in the jungle
for six years,
and now you're telling me
you just sprained
your entire ankle
on a piece of moss?
Get real.
- Well, she threw a shoe.
That means I'm gonna
have to shoot her.
- Yep.
- That's Bob's department.
That's all we need.
- That's all we need!
- We're going to have to
slow down for her.
- Got any ideas?
( GROWLING )
- Oh, it's just my watch.
It growls
at the top of the hour.
( CHUCKLING )
- Oh, Jerry, hey, would you
hand me that Brannock device?
Okay, now, this is a nine,
and I already have it in a ten.
- Snuggy, Snuggy!
- Ooh.
- Whew.
- You'd better rest there
for a few minutes more, Greta.
- A few minutes more?
- It'll be dark pretty soon,
and we're a long ways
from the plane.
- We're going
just as fast as we can,
and that's just as fast
as we're gonna go.
- He's right, Mike.
We've got to get going.
- Oh, shut up!
I'll have to be all right.
- Well, then,
come on, let's go.
Come on.
- Okay, Galahad,
get moving.
- Don't you ever call me
Galahad again, ever.
- Meanwhile, in an equally
racist Tarzan movie
across the way--
- Hey, you, ho-daddy,
surf's up.
- Oh, cool leopard.
I wonder if it's deaf.
( LEOPARD GROWLING )
( BOTS SHOUTING )
- Decent dude.
- Def Leopard.
- Peace, man.
- Can't we stop?
- Sure.
- Just a minute.
- Hold it.
- I am.
I haven't seen a port-a-potty
in ten miles.
- There we go.
- Here, just sit on this
conveniently placed stump.
- All right?
- Mm-hm.
May I have some water?
- Sure.
- White goddess
having trouble?
- White fascist getting smart?
- You're gonna make
one wise crack too many,
and then you're not gonna feel
like making anymore wise cracks.
- Yeah, and if we keep
stopping for her,
we won't make any cracks,
wise or otherwise.
- Ooh, good one.
- You've gotta go
one without me, Mike.
- Are you serious?
- Yes, there's still
a chance for you two;
and if Oolonga and the natives
catch up with me,
maybe I'll still have
enough power to save myself.
- Hm, okay, bye.
- Why not do
as she says, Mike?
They won't harm her.
She's the white goddess.
She can bluff
her way out of it.
It's our only chance.
- Forget it.
- But how are you--
- I said forget it!
- Forgotten, sir.
- They haven't
caught us so far.
We'll just keep
our fingers crossed.
Atta girl.
It'll be dark pretty soon.
If we're gonna
get out of here alive,
we'll have to use our heads.
So, if you've got any ideas,
now's the time to spill them.
- Up to now, my ideas
haven't carried much weight.
So, I'll leave it
to you two masterminds.
- Mm-hm.
- Okay, I had that one coming.
- Well, there's only
one thing we can do.
We'll never make it
through the jungle at night.
We'll have to build a fire
to keep the animals away
and stay close to it
until dawn.
- Are you crazy?
That's all we need is a fire
to tell the locals where we are.
- Oolonga and the natives
will be doing the same thing
we're doing.
- Yeah, that's what
I was thinking, you know.
- Building a fire and staying
close to it for safety.
- How do you know they will?
- I know their superstitions
and their fears.
- Yeah, I would--
hey, I'm talking here!
- And there on handle
was spear.
- Ooh.
- No, really.
( GROWLING )
- Hey, where the hell
is the MGM one?
I've got a film to make.
- You think
you've got problems?
I'm opening for
Siegfried and Roy.
( GROWLING )
- I hate Mondays.
- Hey, wait for me.
I've got a cameo
in this film.
Wait up!
- You think Mellencamp
is a dumb name?
- Really?
- So there on the handle
was a hook.
- Ooh.
- No, really.
- Why don't you try to get
some sleep, Greta?
- I'm not tired.
- Are you kidding?
You're so tired,
you're about ready
to come apart.
- Well, maybe I am,
but I could sit up all night
talking about home.
Tell me some more, Mike.
- Ooh, you are hungry.
- About everything
that's Pearl Harbor.
What else would you
like to know?
- I just love listening
to their voices.
- What kind of hats
are the women wearing?
- Hats?
- Uh-huh.
- Why would you ask me
a thing like that?
How would I know anything
about women's hats?
I never look at their hats.
- Their underwear, yes.
- Anyway, are they cute?
- Greta, they're hats,
you know.
- Oh, don't pretend
you haven't worn any, Reeves.
I can't tell you
anymore than that.
You know something?
- What?
- Hats.
- They'd look
all right on you.
- Hey, you guys.
Why don't you get some sleep?
What are you talking about?
- Hats.
- Mm, golly, it'll be good
to get back to a good hot tub.
( CHUCKLING )
- Maybe sooner than you think.
- Get some sleep.
- Boom!
- What about you?
- I'll keep an eye
on our boyfriend over there.
- He's your boyfriend.
You're the one
who invited the boss angle.
( MONKEY CHATTERING )
- Hey, quit laughing back there.
( SIGHS )
- Uh, say, Bill,
don't look now.
I think your kneecaps
are on fire.
- Here, my little rag doll.
- Did you leave
a wake-up call?
- Well, I'm off.
The jungle extending me
a welcome.
- Heh- heh-heh.
- He's really a good man,
and tomorrow is another day.
- Uh, well, I think
I'll just burn this, uh,
drive-in bank canister here.
- Hmph.
- Smells good.
- So, every time
I eat a burger,
an acre of this stuff
disappears?
I don't get it.
- I'm, uh, ready again.
- Watch that hand.
- Look out, he's got a gun!
Oh, sorry.
( GROWLING )
- Hey, pipe down.
This is the smoking section.
( THEME MUSIC PLAYING )
- Bob, Mike, please,
this isn't getting us anywhere.
Please!
- What the heck
is going on here?
- Go away, they're asleep.
They wake up, they're beating
the cheese out of each other.
- Must be the heat.
- Yeah.
- Now, I'll just take these
things and get out of here.
- Yeah.
- Whoa, Mike,
he really kicked your butt.
- Mike, Mike.
- That could've been
on pay per view.
- Oh, no, shouldn't have
stopped for breakfast.
You had to order
French fried potatoes.
( GRUMBLING )
My fault.
- Hm? Where is he?
- He's gone.
And the gun
and the compass?
- They're gone, too.
- We'll never find the plane
without that compass!
- I'll rub you on a rock,
and you'll magnetize.
- Let's go.
- He went through those bushes.
- Oh, could you be
a little more vague?
- Let's go.
- Is it all right for me to say
he took his pit helmet?
- Uh, yes.
But not now.
- Crickets,
I hear crickets.
Big crickets!
( GROWLING )
Hm?
- Oh!
( GUNSHOT )
- Take that.
- Don't forget to limp.
- Yeah.
-  How's the ankle?
- Oh, all right.
- Good girl.
- Keep hobbling,
or I'll have to chew it off.
- You know, I'd really
like to get a hold
of that Gary Larson guy
once and for all.
- Yeah.
- You ever get pieces of flesh
caught in your teeth?
- I hate that.
- Mm, fresh tracks,
and one of them is limping.
( SPEAKING IN NATIVE LANGUAGE )
- Hey, wait for us.
They wouldn't take our visa.
- What the heck?
Duh!
- Oh, I forgot to wind
my compass.
Now I'm really gonna be late.
- Geez, I hope none of
my friends see me with her.
- Hi, it's me again.
Hope you're enjoying the show,
brought to you
by our friends at Hub West.
- If this is a first date,
you don't mind
if I don't call you again,
do you?
- Oh, my ankle.
It's hot,
and it hurts and stuff.
- No, we've got to keep going.
If he gets too far ahead,
we'll never find him.
- I have a confession to make.
We lost the trail
four miles back.
- Look, Greta.
- Oh, heck,
that could be anybody's.
- We're on the right track.
Come on.
- Oh, that's great, Mike.
What else can we do with it?
- Are we still
in this film or what?
- That's him!
Oh, no, oh.
Hey, where's Ted Bessell?
- Hm?
- Let's watch the fun.
( GUNSHOT )
- Oh, great,
he killed a coconut.
- In cold milk.
- Yeah.
- Come on, honey.
- What did you call me, Mike?
- Why, I called you--
I'm sorry, Greta.
- Oh, brother.
Bungle in the jungle.
- Hear coconut fall.
What's going on?
- Mm.
( MONKEY SCREAMING )
- Oh, stop screaming.
I didn't even hit you.
- Someone oughta
spank that monkey.
- Here, whitey, whitey,
whitey, whitey, whitey.
- Here Caucasian.
Here Caucasian.
- Here, whitey,
whitey, whitey.
- Sprinkle trail
with Cheez Whiz,
white bread, Velveeta.
White devil can't resist.
( GROWLING )
- Hey, remember that time
you took a potshot at me,
pretty boy?
Well, it's time to ante up.
Dig?
( GUNSHOT )
- Take that,
you stinking coconut.
- Uh, can't go
through there, uh, no.
( GRUNTING )
Oh, I'm sick of you old vines.
Oh, meant to do that.
- Heh, an entire jungle,
and I slip on a banana peel.
That's irony for you.
( GROWLING )
- And I'm still right over
your shoulder, smart guy.
- Old coconut, take that.
( GUNSHOT )
- Hm, sounded like
a car backfiring, didn't it?
- Yeah, that ankle healed quick.
( CHUCKLING )
- Continuity--
script girl.
- I invade Poland and--
oh, Goebbels.
- Sieg heil.
- Where are you mine buddies?
( MONKEY SCREAMING )
- Oh, quit screaming.
I'm sorry about the coconut.
- Uh, try to replace
your divots, please.
- Really?
- We're on our way!
- Hey, you two,
he's over there.
- Uh, somebody didn't
replace their divots.
- They're in this movie.
- We made it.
There's the plane.
- We're on our way.
- And it's just landing.
- Hmph, must get off set.
Working overtime.
- Those two just don't get along
with each other, do they?
- Mm-mm.
- Ooh, bingo.
( GUNSHOT )
- My first kill feels good.
( SPEAKING NATIVE LANGUAGE )
- All white people evil.
Let's get out of here, Scooby.
- He's dead.
The poor devil.
He must've gone
completely out of his mind.
- He's dead.
She's mine.
I'm in love.
We're outta here!
Goodnight!
- Hey, it looks like
your in-laws are coming.
- Uh-oh.
- Oolonga! Oolonga!
TOGETHER:
Hail, Dorothy.
The wicked witch doctor is dead.
- Looks even realer
taking off.
- Okay, new rule.
No white people.
Must take hard line with this,
no exceptions.
Send memo.
- I told you this thing had
an automatic pilot.
( CHUCKLING )
( SNORING )
- Wait'll you get a look
at that country, Greta.
Colorado is the most beautiful
state in the whole union--
and that ranch
I've got picked out.
Alfalfa, wheat--
- Stymie, Spanky.
- Hey, you aren't listening
to a word I'm saying.
- Sounds great.
- What are you thinking about?
- Oh, just wondering
how I'm going to look
in one of those hats.
- Huh?
- Hats again.
- Hats?
( LAUGHTER )
- ♪ There was a bungle
In the jungle ♪
♪ That caused
A real big fright ♪
♪ Someone was made a goddess
And she happened to be white ♪
♪ But then she was rescued
And now she's in the States ♪
♪ She's just
Your average housewife ♪
♪ Cleanin' up the place ♪
♪ My
- My ♪
- ♪ My
- ♪ My white goddess ♪
( APPLAUSE )
- Well, you can just tell them,
if they're not
going to worship me,
I'm not going to
join their PTA!
( LAUGHTER )
- Hi, honey, I'm home.
( APPLAUSE )
- Oh, how was work today?
- Boy, it's a jungle
out there.
( LAUGHTER )
- Well, aren't you going to
bow down and kiss my feet?
- Hey, you may be
queen of the jungle,
but I wear the khakis
around here.
( LAUGHTER AND APPLAUSE )
- Hey, what's this mess?
- Oh, it's our neighbor,
that friend of yours.
- Bill?
Did he go on another
wild shooting spree?
- I'll say he did,
and this time
he went too far.
He went and shot up
my crockpot.
I'm not going to be able
to make dinner.
- Well, I told you
he wasn't such a bad guy.
( LAUGHTER )
( KNOCKING )
- I wish that man would learn
how to use the doorbell.
( LAUGHTER )
( KNOCKING )
- Hello, everybody.
( APPLAUSE )
- Will you cut that out?
- Oh, now, stop it you two.
Stop it.
Would you settle down?
Mr. and Mrs. Mabuta
are on their way over here
to play bridge.
- Oh, where?
( GUNSHOT )
- Ooga!
( AUDIENCE GASPING )
- Maybe it'll be
three-card Monty now.
( LAUGHTER )
- Oh, I'm so sorry, Mrs. Mabuta,
that we shot your husband.
What were his last words?
- Mabuta, Mabuta, Mabuta.
- What did she say?
- Sounded like Mabuta,
Mabuta, Mabuta.
- Well, that's one native
that's not going to be
restless tonight.
( LAUGHTER )
- Baby, you're a goddess.
- Aw!
( APPLAUSE )
- Mm, how sweet it is!
Tom Servo!
Art Crow!
Sheila McGypsy!
The Miami Beach audience
is the greatest audience
in the world!
Goodnight, everybody!
( CHEERING AND APPLAUSE )
( FRANK LAUGHING )
- Frank!
- Oh, that was funny, man.
That was even funnier
than the Occasional Wife,
even CPO Sharkey.
- Listen, you hockey puck.
They've got letters to read.
- Okay.
- Sure, uh, I've got them
right here.
I really appreciate
you scientists
faxing these up for us,
but this one is from
Margaret Bannister, okay?
And show that
on the still store, Cambot.
- See that cute picture
and everything.
- "Dear Joel,
I like your movies.
You're really funny.
I'm five years old."
Really, everything
you want to know
about people
when they write.
"Crow is really funny--"
- Thank you.
- "And Tom is, too."
- And I don't know--
she must've forgot about you,
Gypsy, but I'm sure she--
- She thinks
you're funny, too, Gypsy.
- I'm sure she would think
you're funny, too,
and she sent us, actually,
two pictures along with a photo.
Put that one on, Cambot.
- Cool!
- That's really nice.
- And then we've got this one,
too, which I really like.
I thought
it was kind of cool
how she just drew it black
where she didn't know
what the bottom
of our bodies looked like.
- That's imagination for you.
- But you see--
- Oh, there it is.
- Yeah, that's what it
looks like.
- Please, my dressing gown.
- Well, I guess that ends
the experiment, sirs.
I hope you enjoyed
the skits and stuff we did.
- Can I, can I--
Joel, can I say the address,
please?
- Oh, yeah, better do that.
- Send your letters,
drawings, and whatever
to the Mystery Science Theater
Information Club,
P.O. Box 5325, Hopkins, MN.
The zip code is 55343.
Keep 'em coming.
- Right.
And I guess that ends
the experiment, sir.
- Well, very nice Clambake.
- Yeah, very nice Clambake.
- Until next time Joel-a-rini.
- Okay, Frank,
push the button.
- What?
- Would you push the button?
- Just push the button.
- Oh.
( THEME MUSIC PLAYING )